# SUHAIB T.MUHSEN

Baghdad . +9647700662537 . suhaibthamer@gmail.com

### Project Manager/ Construction Manager

Su	m	m	a	rv
_ ~			•	- ,

A Civil Engineer with 8+ years of experience. Capable of working independently with minimum supervision, and committed to providing high quality service to every project, with focus on health, safety and environmental issues. Professional, capable, and motivated individual who consistently performs in challenging environments.

## **Technical Summary**

#### Ability to:

- Lead, organize, supervise, and evaluate the work of staff.
- Independently plan, perform and coordinate advanced level professional and technical engineering studies, computations, drawings, reports and surveys.
- Interpret, explain, and enforce department policies and procedures.
- Analyze problems and develop effective alternatives for their solutions.
- Oversee and coordinate the work of consultants and contractors.
- Write clear, concise and accurate technical and non-technical reports, correspondence and memoranda; prepare reports, agreements and accurate records.
- Prepare accurate plans, specifications, cost estimates and engineering reports and make accurate engineering computations and drawings.
- Coordinate engineering and construction activities with activities of other divisions and outside organizations.
- Take coaching, instruction, and feedback with a cooperative and positive attitude.
- Deal tactfully with the public, high level staff or other public and private agencies, contractors, private engineers, governmental officials and other City employees.
- Explain complicated technical matters in non-technical terms.
- Work independently in the absence of supervision.
- Understand and follow oral and written instructions.
- Communicate clearly and concisely, both orally and in writing.
- Establish and maintain effective working relationships with those contacted in the course of work
- Well handling for the INVOISs ,BOQs ,MARs and SPCMs
- Emailing and office jobs.

#### **Applications**

- Microsoft Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint
- Project
- Outlook

# Work experience

2017 - 2019	project Manager  FCO GROUP(www.fcogroup.com) / Basra-Zubair Oilfield  Clients: ZFOD, ENI, BHGE, OILSERV, NPS, DRAKE&SCULL  Type of projects: work over, water injection, DGS, skids, diesel tanks, steel structure buildings and concrete buildings
2016 - 2017	site manager  FCO GROUP(www.fcogroup.com) / Basra-Zubair Oilfield  Clients: ZFOD, ENI, BHGE, OILSERV, NPS, DRAKE&SCULL  Type of projects: work over, water injection, DGS, skids, diesel tanks, steel structure buildings and concrete buildings
2015 - 2016	liaison officer  Aegis Defence Services / GARDA WORLD (www.garda.com)/Baghdad  clients: MOI, US EMBASSY
2014 - 2015	QC Civil Inspector  ALMCO GROUP(www.almcogroup.com)/Basra-west Qurna  Clients: exsonmobile, flour, saipem  Type of projects: pipe lines
2013 - 2014	QC Civil Inspector  cadini group(www.cadinigroup.com) / Baghdad  Client: Baghdad investment  Type of projects: Zawraa Amusement Park, Infrastructure
2012 - 2013	site Coordinator  open project co (www.openproject.co) / Karbalaa  Client: MOY  Type of projects: Karblaa Olympic stadium
2011 - 2012	Site Engineer  janat alfalah & nahj alhadarah/ Baghdad  clients: World Bank  Type of projects: Hospital, schools

# Education

2007 - 2011 Bachelor of civil Engineering *Al-Nahrain University* 

### References

Yamman Hassan Ali <Yamman.Ali@oilserv.com>
Rami AbuMaria <Rami.AbuMaria@dsi-oilgas.com>
Sabri, Sinan Z <sinan.sabri@bhge.com>
petergati@cadinigroup.com

CMO\_I.G1Basrah@garda.com kareem.alshemaree@almcogroup.com